One of the greatest heroes in American history never fired a bullet.
Hacksaw Ridge is a drama, history, war film directed by Mel Gibson.
WWII American Army Medic Desmond T.
Doss, who served during the Battle of Okinawa, refuses to kill people and becomes the first
Conscientious Objector in American history to receive the Congressional Medal of Honor.
Desmond T. Doss, played by Andrew Garfield.
Captain Glover, played by Sam Worthington.
Sgt Howell, played by Vince Vaughn.
Dorothy Schuttle, played by Teresa Palmer.
Smitty Ryker, played by Luke Bracey.
Tom Doss, played by Hugo Weaving.
Hacksaw Ridge is a 2016 epic biographical war film directed by Mel Gibson, and starring Andrew Garfield as Desmond Doss, an American combat medic in World War II who, as a Seventh-day
Adventist, refused to use a weapon of any kind; Doss became the first conscientious objector to be awarded the Medal of Honor, for his service during the Battle of Okinawa.
The film was written by Andrew Knight and Robert Schenkkan, based
on the 2004 documentary The Conscientious Objector.
The supporting cast includes Sam Worthington, Luke Bracey, Teresa
Palmer, Hugo Weaving, Rachel Griffiths, and Vince Vaughn.
Filming took place in Australia from September to December 2015.
Following its premiere at the 73rd Venice International Film Festival on September 4,
2016, Hacksaw Ridge was released in the United States on November 4.
It grossed over $180 million worldwide, and received critical acclaim, with
Gibson's direction and Garfield's performance earning particular praise.
It was widely viewed as a return to form for Gibson, whose career
had been in decline following several controversies.
Hacksaw Ridge was chosen by the National Board of Review and American Film Institute as one of their
top ten films of 2016 respectively, and received numerous awards and nominations.
At the 89th Academy Awards, the film received six nominations, including Best
Picture, winning for Best Sound Mixing and Best Film Editing.
It also received three Golden Globe nominations and twelve nominations at the
Australian Academy Awards, winning nine of them including Best Film.
The film explores themes of japan, hero, world war
ii, abusive father, affectation.
The tone is emotional.